This is Trigun.
Oh, my God.
You
Him again?
Something has to be done!
Gotta get some help.
Meryl, I don't see a soul anywhere.
Nobody told me this became a ghost town.
I didn't hear anybody
say anything about that.
I really hope there's a well around it.
Wishful thinking doesn't help.
Just don't think about it.
It only makes the truth more painful.
You were right, the truth hurts.
I hate being right.
Huh?
Land subsidence?
Tarnation!
First the war dries up, then that dang
criminal, the humanoid typhoon, shows up.
This town ain't fit to live in no more.
Yeah, bash the stampede.
The new hired gun at Saison.
Oh, shut.
This town is finished.
Bad times are here.
Hmm. Merrill. Uh-huh.
All right.
I'm so excited.
Now we can get water from that mansion.
Oh, I give up.
Excuse me.
Is this the Cesar residence?
My name is Merrill Stryfe,
and I'm here on behalf?
of the Bernardelli Insurance Society.
I'd like to talk to you
for a minute, please.
Yeah, and I'm her partner, Millie
Thompson, and we're very thirsty.
Hey, don't say that.
I just need to ask you a few
questions about Vash the Stampede.
I heard that he was staying here.
Thank you very much.
Yes, we certainly appreciate this.
Hello?
Uh-oh.
Hey, what are you doing here?
You're not supposed to be here.
I work here now. I'm Mr.
Cliff's hired bodyguard, and
I'm his exclusive ace gunman.
Hey, is that for me? How nice.
Oh, you shouldn't have.
You're really a bodyguard?
These are good.
I can't believe it.
We're happy to see you
again, Mr. Ace Gunman.
It's an amazing coincidence.
These are really delicious.
Would you like one?
Well, yes, I'd love one. Huh?
You have got to keep your
mind on business, Millie.
Huh?
All right, Ace, I want to know.
What's your real reason for being here?
Hmm...
Well, now that was an odd response.
Excuse me, I don't mean to interrupt you,
but are these young ladies
friends of yours, Vash?
What? Vash?
He's not Vash!
What the hell are you talking about?
In any event, you two seem
to be here for a reason.
Huh?
We shouldn't be discussing this out here.
Won't you please come in?
Uh, yeah, but I don't think that we...
My name is Cliff Cesar.
I make my living selling
water in this town,
but recently somebody's
been trying to kill me.
That could be bad for
business and my health.
So I advertise for a good bodyguard,
for someone tough and smart
like Vash the Stampede.
I originally put his name down as a joke.
It never occurred to me
that it would be taken
seriously and that the real
thing would actually show up.
Isn't that right, Vash?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's me, all right.
Now that I'm here, you
have nothing to fear.
The man who will slaughter the innocent!
Does the most evil of
evil deeds with a price
of 60 billion double dollars on his head?
Yes, I am that man!
What a nice, dependable
guy, and modest as well.
Isn't it wonderful?
With Bash around, the people
of the mansion will be safe.
This may sound rude, but I think
you should have your eyes checked.
Now listen, young lady, it's very
important that I have a good bodyguard.
Let me explain to you
just how important it is.
Her name is Marianne Alekhuizen.
She's the granddaughter of the
head of the Stantal Federal Bureau,
and she's staying at
the mansion as my guest.
The truth is, we had an attempted
break-in here five days ago,
and frankly, I'm a little worried.
I wouldn't have hired a bodyguard if
I thought they were coming after me,
but Marianne's safety
is my responsibility,
and I do not want
anything happening to her.
Well, now you know the whole story,
and that is why I need your help.
You can definitely count on me, Mr.
Cliff.
I don't let anyone in my sights get away,
and I'm known for my bullets
never missing their mark,
especially if it's the
heart of a beautiful lady.
Hey
I'm happy to have you protect me mr.
Vash.
I really am.
Oh, yeah A lot of people say
that I hear it all the time.
Is that right?
I believe it
I Need to talk to you?
What's the matter my dear
listen to me mr. Cliff.
I think you're a nice man
How can you believe that weird guy
out there is Vash the Stampede,
the legendary gunman?
That droopy-eyed, cocky,
upside-down-haired,
women-chasing lunatic
who's nuts for donuts
and gorges them like
a starved hog in heat.
You honestly think it's him?
She's really very nice.
She bought the donuts.
She's really very nice and loud.
I am telling you for the last time,
you are being deceived by that man!
On the contrary, I'm
doing the deceiving. Huh?
I think you got a good look at the city.
With that kind of mess out there,
all it took was a simple
little rumor that Vash
the Stampede was working
for me as a bodyguard.
The town folk panicked
and headed for the hills,
and I'm expecting my enemy to do the same.
Hello?
This ad of yours caught my eye.
Well, congratulations.
As of today, you are now
Vash the Stampede. Huh?
Vash the Stampede, it's
a pleasure to meet you.
It could have been anybody.
He just showed up.
I see.
He's a huge inconvenience,
but using him in your plan this
way makes a lot more sense.
Actually, this whole thing's gone
a lot farther than I expected.
The scoundrel who's been
after me is a tall, blond man,
packing a silver weapon and a
reputation as an ace gunfighter.
Huh?
Did you hear that, Millie?
Yes, I did. Every word.
This is an absolute godsend.
What humorous people they are.
Yeah, it's usually best just
to leave airheads alone.
Hey, you know, Mr.
Cliff,
if you don't mind, My partner Millie and
I would like to be your bodyguards too,
For extra protection
only naturally we won't
demand to feel like that
greedy faker over there,
so there'd be no risk to you whatsoever?
Well, that'd be fine with me.
Thank you, sir.
You won't be sorry
This is not what I expected
to do as a bodyguard
every journey begins with a single step.
We just have to have patience
Is it ready yet?
We'll take it out when
it is wow scary later
I'd like to show that guy something scary.
Nothing has gone right since we met him.
I don't think that's true at all.
I'm having a wonderful time.
Plus, we get the hell to
all the water we can drink.
Boy, has she got a short fuse.
I can hear the sound of running water.
And I believe it's coming from
the shower in Mary Ann's room.
Lifeline secure?
When favorable, the plan is perfect.
I've got the guts.
I'm coming, Marianne!
Miss Marianne, the supper is...
Where are you?
Oh.
Hello.
What in the world are you doing
hanging outside the window?
I'm, uh, well, diligently
patrolling the roof area for spooks.
Yeah, that's it. Oh, wow.
That sounds scary.
You bodyguards sure are busy people.
Oh, yeah, I almost forgot to tell you.
Supper's ready.
Thanks a lot.
This is Mr. Cliff's study.
Marianne.
Ah, this place sure is fancy.
Is water really that profitable, Mr.
Cliff?
There's been a drought
for the past few years.
I'm very lucky to have been
able to enjoy a few luxuries.
Because my father, who was a plant engineer,
purchased land with a water supply.
It's a rare commodity around here.
I'd imagine that would tend to
make a lot of people jealous.
Yep, I'm afraid a lot of
folks want my water rights.
Apparently,
they think I'm monopolizing
it for selfish reasons
and don't want to share
the wealth with them.
But the water supply is not limitless.
Unless it's managed properly by someone
who knows how, it will completely dry up.
But it doesn't change the fact that
you're profiting from a natural resource.
I'm sorry, it's none of my business.
No, you're absolutely right, my dear.
But I can't let the water be stolen by
reckless people who don't
care if it dries up.
They may call me a coward, but I intend
to do what it takes to protect the water!
That's most admirable, Mr.
Cliff
Please excuse me, Mr.
Cliff, I'm not feeling very well I
think I'm going to go to bed early.
She may look calm, but she's
probably feeling quite ill at ease.?
Perhaps it was not such a
good idea to invite her here.
Uh, I suppose.
Well, I think I'll make the rounds
and make sure this place is secure.
I should at least pretend to
look like a real bodyguard.
As an extra safety measure, I've asked
Marianne to keep her curtain drawn. You...
I...
I would never dream of
doing anything like...
I mean, good thinking.
Very sensible idea, Mr.
Cliff.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Later!
I'm really exhausted, Meryl, from
all the cooking we had to do today.
This is only the beginning.
There's no telling when
the culprit will show up.
We have to be alert in our duties.
There'll be no sleeping for us tonight?
May I come in?
One moment, please!
Come in.
Excuse me, something wrong?
Uh, no.
Were you looking at the stars?
Yes, I was thinking.
Even though most of my memories
there are unpleasant ones.
Thoughts of home, whether good or bad,
are positive indicators
of a journey of the heart.
It's always been my dream to travel
by myself to any place I want.
But I could never persuade
my father to let me do it.
So I've only been allowed to stay
at the homes of his closest friends.
This is hardly what I'd call a
journey of the heart, you know?
Oh?
Someday, you'll be able to take
a journey to anywhere you desire.
Although it may not
exactly be by yourself.
I'm not sure I understand
what you mean by that.
Oh, I think I just saw something move.
There it is again!
Wait here.
I'll go have a look. Are you sure?
It's my job, ma 'am.
Dammit!
That hurt, you stupid idiot.
Stay still!
It's the end!
It's Vash the Stampede!
Let go of me! I'll sue you!
You have no idea who you're dealing with!
What are you doing?
Huh?
Hey, why the hell did you
just attack me, you maniac?
Oh, gee, it's only you.
What do you mean, it's only me?
How rude!
Marianne and I were having a
heated discussion about our
future when we were interrupted
by the sound of an intruder.
I just came out to investigate.
So what did I ever do to you?
Now that you've apprehended the intruder,
do you feel like you have
a nice, clean conscience?
Well, not when it comes to Marianne.
Okay, well, I had no idea the two
of you were on such friendly terms.
Have you been paying any attention at all?
Hey, Miss Marianne!
You don't have to worry your little head!
I have captured the culprit, so
all is safe and well for you again!
Who are you calling a culprit?
Anything? No.
I don't understand what's going on.
Both Miss Marianne and Mr.
Cliff have just disappeared,
apparently without a trace.
Do you think that they were kidnapped?
We were outside the entire time.
I think that's pretty much impossible.
Oh, I'm so worried about them. Meryl!
They're nowhere to be found. What is that?
Miss Marianne's dress
and some bloody bandages.
There was a man that tried
to break in five days ago.
Then we find a discarded dress
and some bloody bandages,
and finally Miss Marianne
was seen sneaking around?
and entering Mr.
Cliff's study. Well,
there's more than enough evidence here to
support the fact that
Marianne has been after him.
You're wrong!
Huh? It can't be!
Marianne just isn't that kind of girl!
How can you be so sure?
From the moment I saw her,
from the look in her eyes, Miss
Marianne has a beautiful heart.
You're the easily deceived type who cries
himself to sleep every night, aren't you?
Thanks a lot dream wrecker I know a ghost
must have gotten Miss Marianne, huh?
You said yourself there were spooks on
the roof when I saw you by the window.
Oh that was i mean uh what i
meant was you know spooks there?
Huh?
Uh, spooks.
What's this about the roof?
He was hanging outside the window
by Miss Marianne's bathroom.
Aha! Yes?
Just what the hell do
you think you were doing?
Peeking into a lady's
room, you disgusting sicko!
Wait!
Time out!
You may think you're slick, Mr.
Hotpants, but you're not gonna
get away with it this time!
Whoa, wait!
Time out! Time out!
Huh?
I knew he wasn't telling the whole truth.
What a naughty little princess?
Even pranks have a limit!
So now they've started using
kids to do their dirty work.
Thanks to your selfish
monopolization of the water supply?
All of the land in this
area has dried up and died.
Do you have any idea how many people
have suffered because of your greed?
So little Miss Marianne
comes to get the evidence.
Justice doesn't come that cheap.
Oh that's right i almost forgot.
I shot.
The people have all evacuated.
So there'll be no witnesses.
Spreading the rumor of Vash the stampede
did my business a world of good.
I have far too much invested
in this place to allow
the likes of you to come
in and ruin things for me.
Game over.
Are you alright?
Idiot is that what he meant
when he said he was gonna sneak
up behind him this mess has
gone from spill to overflow?
Great under these conditions.
There's absolutely nothing we can do now.
Oh Well, this explains
your little luxuries.
Ha!
You're wasting my time here. Run!
Get out of here, quick!
Hurry!
Thank goodness!
I knew it!
You are the girl I thought you were!
Well, very brave.
Shhh!
Terry!
Oh, damn you!
He reads the trajectories of the bullets
by watching the gun movements and timing.
It's sad!
Just no skill.
Eww!
What the hell are you, anyway?
I'm your bodyguard and his
gunman, just as advertised.
Not bad.
I guess I was right after
all when I chose to hire you.
Don't you agree?
What? Hm?
How dare you?
As requested, I have
protected your guest, Mr.
Cliff.
But look there!
Huh?
Good job, Meryl! We did it! Shut up!
This is no time for congratulations!
It's all right.
The dammed water just overflowed
all at once, that's all.
It's not your fault.
It will return underground eventually
and make the town prosper again.
And I'm sure everyone who left will
be able to return to their homes.
I'm very grateful.
You're welcome.
Come on!
All it was was a series of
lucky accidents, that's all.
Did you dodge all those
bullets just by accident?
Or did you do it on purpose?
I suppose it was more
like a fluke, actually.
Because if you did that consciously, I'm
afraid I'd really have to believe that...
You are, in fact, the
legendary Vash the Stampede.
And what if I was Vash the Stampede?
Then I'd arrest you.
I have the both of you to thank as well.
You must be glad it's over.
Your job's completed.
Unfortunately, we've just
gone back to square one.
Oh, Meryl, don't let it get to you.
Are you leaving?
My job's done here.
There goes the bodyguard with no name.
I could really fall for that guy.
He's a real man.
What do you mean?
That guy is completely irresponsible.
I'm afraid you have no
eye for men. Says who?
Maybe someday I'll show
you, then you'll see.
I have absolutely no desire
to see, thank you very much.
Now, Meryl, don't let it get to you.
I was so sure it would work out this time.
She was such a Kaite.
But I guess there's no
way it could have worked.
I don't want to get arrested.
This one will probably
be blamed on me, too.
Oh, man.
The blue sky in the sky, the
wind is coming to the future.
The day of the day,
the sun is coming
to the
future.
Those who make mistakes blame
themselves and close their hearts!
It's impossible to fix
the mistake men can't
return to the past that's
why they drink luscious
drunks sliding alcohol
down their throats to
dilute the memories
that can't be forgotten.
Frank Marlin the gunsmith does nothing.
of a drink.
And he questions the
glass after it's empty.
Am I wrong?
Was I wrong?